A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Press Materials FA1322
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Record Group 2, Accession 2018:088, 1953-2002; 2; 32.15 Cubic Feet 34 LTR size, 1 Half-LTR size, 40 LGL size, and 1 Half-LGL size Hollinger boxes
  - Press releases, 1955-1993; 1; 10.25 Cubic Feet 24 LTR size Hollinger boxes, 1 Half-LTR size Hollinger box, and 2 LGL size Hollinger boxes
    - Education and Culture Program subject press release files, 1956-1981; 1; 4.555 Cubic Feet 1 LGL size Hollinger box and about 10.75 LTR size Hollinger boxes
      - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) release, 1975 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) release, 1974 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) Ford Foundation release - $8.2 million grant, 1971 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) Ford Foundation release - $3.7 million grant, 1970 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) Announcement of Aid to Individual Scholars, circa 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) Ford Foundation release - $5,670,000 grant, 1960 December 27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) Ford Foundation release - $88,500 grant, 1957 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) release - $2,600,000 grant, 1957 January 24 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - The American Dance Machine release - $45,240 grant, 1979 October (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - American Historical Association release - $96,000 grant, 1956 April (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - American Music Center list of commissions, 1968 July (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - American Music Center release - Third group of commissions, 1960 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - American Music Center release - Second group of commissions, 1959 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - American Music Center release - First group of commissions, 1959 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - American Music Center excerpt from booklet - $210,000 grant, 1957 October (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - American Music Center Ford Foundation release - $210,000 grant, 1957 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - American Operatic Repertoire Program current list of works, 1975 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - American Operatic Repertoire Program Ford Foundation release - $950,000 appropriation, 1959 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - American Philosophical Association Ford Foundation release - $25,000 grant, 1957 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - American Place Theater, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
        Note in original folder: For Press Release see "Cash Reserve Grants" release dated 10/18/71 - FF Letter dated 12/1/71.
      - American Place Theater Ford Foundation release - $474,000 grant, 1967 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - American Place Theater Ford Foundation release - $225,000 grant, 1964 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - American Repertory Theater release - $50,000 grant, 1979 November (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - American School of Classical Studies Ford Foundation release - $23,000, 1974 January (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - American School of Classical Studies Ford Foundation release - $43,500 and $20,000, 1972 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - American School of Classical Studies Ford Foundation release - $15,000 grant, 1971 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - American Symphony Orchestra League release - $360,000 grant, 1968 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Archives of American Art Ford Foundation release - $250,000 grant, 1959 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Archives of American Art release - $250,000 grant, 1959 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Arena Stage release - $742,542 cash reserve, 1973 July (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Arena Stage Ford Foundation release - Cash reserve, 1973 July 9 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Arena Stage release - $250,000 grant, 1968 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Arena Stage Ford Foundation release - $96,450 grant, 1966 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Art-Macedonian Artistic Society Ford Foundation release - $68,400, 1972 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Art Students' League of New York release - $153,025 grant, 1968 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Art Students' League of New York Ford Foundation release - $250,000 grant, 1967 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Arts of the Theater Foundation Ford Foundation release, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Arts of the Theater Foundation Ford Foundation release - $9,200 grant, 1967 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Arts of the Theater Foundation release - $75,000 grant, 1964 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - Asolo State Theater Company release - Cash reserve grant, 1972 October-November (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Athens Technological Organization Ford Foundation release - $150,000, 1974 January (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Athens Technological Organization Ford Foundation release - $37,000, 1972 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Athens Technological Organization Ford Foundation release - $264,000 grant, 1970 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns Program cumulative list of awards, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns Program release - Eighth year awards, 1969 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns program release - Seventh year awards, 1968 August 12 (Box 1, Folder 55)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns Program release - Sixth year awards, 1967 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns Program release - Fifth year awards, 1966 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns Program release - Fourth year awards, 1965 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns Program release - Third year awards, 1964 August 3 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns Program release - Second year awards, 1963 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns Program release - First year awards, 1962 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - Ford Foundation Administrative Interns Program - Initial announcement, 1961 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 62)
      - American Federation of Arts - The Ideal Theatre: Eight Concepts, undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
      - American Federation of Arts Ford Foundation release - $488,000, 1967 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - American Federation of Arts Ford Foundation release - $511,500, 1966 October 13 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - American Federation of Arts release - $511,500, 1966 October 13 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - American Federation of Arts release - Theater design exhibit announcement, 1961 December 28 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - American Federation of Arts list of grantees under Artists-in-Residence Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - American Federation of Arts release - Retrospective shows first year awards, 1959 February 27 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - American Federation of Arts list of retrospective exhibitions program participants, 1969 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      - American Federation of Arts itinerary - The Ideal Theater: Eight Concepts, 1963 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - American Federation of Arts Ford Foundation release - $253,000 grant, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - American Federation of Arts release - $253,000 grant, 1958 November 5 (Box 2, Folder 73)
        Note on original folder read:
        See Also: List of grantees under this program
      - American Federation of Arts release - Second year of Artists-in-Residence program, 1964 October 21 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - American Federation of Arts release - $172,000 grant, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - American Film Institute (AFI) release - $100,000 grant, 1980 July (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - American Film Institute (AFI) release - Independent Filmmaker Program, 1973 August 16 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - American Film Institute (AFI) release - $800,000 grant, 1971 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - American Film Institute (AFI) release - $1.3 million grant, 1967 June 5 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - American Plays Program 1978-1979 list of awards and plays, 1981 March 20 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - American Plays Program 1978-1979 list of awards, 1978 December (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - American Plays Program Ford Foundation release - 1978-1979 recipients, 1978 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      - American Plays Program 1977-1978 list of awards, 1980 October 20 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - American Plays Program 1976-1977 list of awards, 1981 March 20 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - American Plays Program Ford Foundation release, 1977 September 19 (Box 2, Folder 85)
      - American Plays Program Ford Foundation release, 1976 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 86)
      - Archaeology, program for Ford Foundation release - $1.5 million for 19 grants to universities and colleges, 1968 May 7 (Box 2, Folder 87)
      - Ballet West, undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
        Note in original folder: For Press Release see "Cash Reserve Grants" release dated 10/18/71 - FF Letter dated 12/1/72
      - Baltimore Opera Company, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
      - Boston Ballet, undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
      - Boston, Opera Company of, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
      - Bowdoin College Ford Foundation release - $36,500 grant for conference, 1966 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 92)
      - Bowdoin College Ford Foundation release - $25,000 grant for conference, 1965 April 5 (Box 2, Folder 93)
      - Bowdoin College release - $36,500 grant for conference, 1966 February (Box 2, Folder 94)
      - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences index of Hardy Holzman report, 1970 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 95)
      - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences Ford Foundation release, 1970 May 26 (Box 2, Folder 96)
      - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences Ford Foundation release - $166,000 grant, 1969 August 27 (Box 2, Folder 97)
      - Brooklyn Academy of Music Ford Foundation release - $100,000 Grant, undated (Box 2, Folder 98)
        Copies Filed Under City Center
      - Brooklyn Museum Ford Foundation release - $50,000 grant, undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
        Note in original folder:
        For Copies See Monographs Program
      - Business Committee for the Arts Ford Foundation release - $225,000 Grant, 1968 October 11 (Box 2, Folder 100)
      - Ballet Development Program release - $2.9 million grant to Pennsylvania Ballet, 1971 May (Box 2, Folder 101)
      - Ballet Development Program Ford Foundation release - $228,500 grant to National Ballet, 1971 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 102)
      - Ballet Development Program release - $350,000 grant to Boston Ballet, 1970 March 12 (Box 2, Folder 103)
      - Ballet Development Program release - $1,165,000 grant to Pennsylvania Ballet, 1969 February-March (Box 2, Folder 104)
      - Ballet Development Program Ford Foundation release - $1,250,000 in grants, 1966 August 1 (Box 2, Folder 105)
      - Ballet Development Program release - $155,000 grant to Joffrey Ballet, 1964 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 106)
      - Ballet Development Program Ford Foundation release - Henry T. Heald statement, 1963 December (Box 2, Folder 107)
      - Ballet Development Program Ford Foundation release - $7,756,000 grant, 1963 December 16 (Box 2, Folder 108)
      - Ballet Society Ford Foundation release - Fellowship program, 1959 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 109)
      - California, University of (Davis) Ford Foundation release $220,000 grant - Study Group on Unity of Knowledge, 1967 June 1 (Box 2, Folder 110)
      - Carnegie Hall Corporation Ford Foundation release - $200,000 grant, 1966 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 111)
      - Center for Arts of Indian America Ford Foundation release - $150,000 grant, 1968 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 112)
      - Center Opera Company, undated (Box 2, Folder 113)
        Note in original folder: For Press Release see "Cash Reserve Grants" release dated 10/18/71 - FF Letter dated 12/1/71
      - Center Opera Company Ford Foundation release - $89,750, 1970 May 26 (Box 2, Folder 114)
      - Center Stage, undated (Box 2, Folder 115)
      - Center Theatre Group release - $865,015 partial cash reserve, 1973 January 24 (Box 2, Folder 116)
      - Chicago Dance Foundation release - $53,846 grant, 1970 December (Box 2, Folder 117)
      - Cincinnati Playhouse in the Park release - cash reserve grant, 1973 June 20 (Box 3, Folder 118)
      - Cincinnati Summer Opera Association, undated (Box 3, Folder 119)
      - Cities/Survey of cultural activities in 105 largest U.S. cities, 1969 July 1 (Box 3, Folder 120)
      - Civic Opera Program Ford Foundation release - $1,727,625 in grants, 1963 October 15 (Box 3, Folder 121)
      - Cleveland Institute of Music release - $1 million grant, 1971 October 5 (Box 3, Folder 122)
      - Cleveland Playhouse, undated (Box 3, Folder 123)
        Note in original folder: For Press Release see "Cash Reserve Grants" release dated (blank) - FF Letter dated 3/1/72
      - Cleveland Playhouse release - $225,000 grant, undated (Box 3, Folder 124)
        Original folder found empty of content.
      - Cleveland Playhouse Ford Foundation release - $30,500 grant, 1959 July 2 (Box 3, Folder 125)
      - Cleveland Playhouse Ford Foundation release - Plans for part in productions, 1958 February 3 (Box 3, Folder 126)
      - Cleveland Playhouse list of grantees, 1967 August 18 (Box 3, Folder 127)
      - Cleveland Playhouse Ford Foundation release - $130,000 grant, 1957 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 128)
        Note on original folder reads:
        See Also: List of grantees under this program.
      - Cleveland Playhouse Ford Foundation release - $130,000 grant, 1957 October (Box 3, Folder 129)
      - College Art Association of America - Availability of "The Visual Arts in Higher Education", undated (Box 3, Folder 130)
      - College Art Association of America Ford Foundation release - $180,000 grant, 1961 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 131)
      - College Art Association of America release - $13,500 grant, 1959 November 30 (Box 3, Folder 132)
      - Columbia University Ford Foundation release - $5,000 grant, 1971 April 23 (Box 3, Folder 133)
      - Columbia University Ford Foundation release - $24,000 grant, 1970 October 2 (Box 3, Folder 134)
      - Columbia University Ford Foundation release - $5,000 grant, 1970 January 2 (Box 3, Folder 135)
      - Columbia University Ford Foundation release - $81,729 grant, 1969 April 9 (Box 3, Folder 136)
      - Columbia University Ford Foundation release - $85,600 grant, 1964 January 22 (Box 3, Folder 137)
      - Committee to Rescue Italian Art Ford Foundation release - $260,000 grant, 1970 January 2 (Box 3, Folder 138)
      - Company for the Development of Cinematography in Greece Ford Foundation release - $104,500, 1972 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 139)
      - Coordinating Council of Literary Magazines (CCLM) release - $439,636, 1976 February 20 (Box 3, Folder 140)
      - Council for Public Schools Ford Foundation release - $184,000 grant, 1970 January 2 (Box 3, Folder 141)
      - Council for Public Schools release - $184,000 grant, 1969 October 26 (Box 3, Folder 142)
      - Council on Foundations release - $100,000 grant, 1968 May 17 (Box 3, Folder 143)
      - Council on Library Resources (CLR) Ford Foundation release - $6 million grant, 1974 June (Box 3, Folder 144)
      - Council on Library Resources (CLR) release - $5 Million grant, 1971 May 22 (Box 3, Folder 145)
      - Council on Library Resources (CLR) Ford Foundation release - $5 million grant, 1967 November 28 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - Council on Library Resources (CLR) release - $5 million grant, 1967 November 28 (Box 3, Folder 147)
      - Council on Library Resources (CLR) Ford Foundation release - $8 million grant, 1961 January 3 (Box 3, Folder 148)
      - Council on Library Resources (CLR) release - $5 million grant, 1956 September (Box 3, Folder 149)
      - Cultural Council Foundation release - $15,000 (FILMOBILE), 1980 August-September (Box 3, Folder 150)
      - Cunningham (Merce) and Dance Company release, 1978 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 151)
      - Ford Foundation Cash Reserve Program - Grants to date and announcements, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 152)
      - Ford Foundation Cash Reserve Program initial release, 1971 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 153)
      - Ford Foundation Cash Reserve Program terms/attachments, A and B/pink, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 154)
      - Ford Foundation Cash Reserve Program terms/attachments, A and B/green, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 155)
      - Ford Foundation Catalogues Program list of grants, 1981 December 31 (Box 3, Folder 156)
      - Ford Foundation Catalogues Program release - Awards, 1971 January 15 (Box 3, Folder 157)
        According to note in original folder, all Catalogues Program press releases were discarded.
      - Ford Foundation Catalogues Program release - Initial Announcement, 1961 October 18 (Box 3, Folder 158)
      - Choral Directors Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1962 June 4 (Box 3, Folder 159)
      - Choral Directors Program Ford Foundation release - Initial announcement, 1961 October 30 (Box 3, Folder 160)
      - City Center of Music and Drama release - $5.3 million grant (part cash reserve), 1974 June (Box 3, Folder 161)
      - City Center of Music and Drama release - $1 million, 1973 March (Box 3, Folder 162)
      - City Center of Music and Drama Ford Foundation release - $285,000 grant, 1968 August 12 (Box 3, Folder 163)
      - City Center of Music and Drama Ford Foundation release - $100,000 grant, 1966 February 23 (Box 3, Folder 164)
      - City Center of Music and Drama release - $3.2 million grant for New York State Theatre, 1965 November 16 (Box 3, Folder 165)
      - City Center of Music and Drama release - $250,000 grant, 1964 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 166)
      - City Center of Music and Drama Ford Foundation release - $35,000 grant, 1963 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 167)
      - City Center of Music and Drama Ford Foundation release - $105,000 grant, 1963 June 13 (Box 3, Folder 168)
      - City Center of Music and Drama Ford Foundation release - $7,000 grant, 1963 January 21 (Box 3, Folder 169)
      - City Center of Music and Drama Ford Foundation release - $310,000 grant, 1958 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 170)
      - City Center of Music and Drama Ford Foundation release - $105,000 grant, 1957 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 171)
      - City Center of Music and Drama - A Contemporary American Operatic Repertoire, $100,000 grant, 1957 October (Box 3, Folder 172)
      - Civic Opera Program release - Grant to Seattle Opera Association, 1966 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 173)
      - Civic Opera Program Ford Foundation release - Grants to Boston and Seattle opera companies, 1966 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 174)
      - Civic Opera Program Ford Foundation release - $103,000 grant to Connecticut Opera Association, 1964 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 175)
      - Concert Artists Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1971 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 176)
      - Concert Artists Program list of awards, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 177)
      - Concert Artists Program list of works and premiers, 1968 August 15 (Box 4, Folder 178)
      - Concert Artists Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1959 March 9 (Box 4, Folder 179)
      - Concert Artists Program Ford Foundation release - Initial announcement, 1958 July 27 (Box 4, Folder 180)
      - Concert Soloists Program list of commissions and Performances, 1969 March 31 (Box 4, Folder 181)
      - Concert Soloists Program Ford Foundation release - $120,000 grant, 1962 June 26 (Box 4, Folder 182)
      - Concert Soloists Program Ford Foundation release - Initial announcement, 1961 October 30 (Box 4, Folder 183)
      - Creative Arts Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 4th year, 1963 February 28 (Box 4, Folder 184)
      - Creative Arts Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 3rd year, 1962 January 22 (Box 4, Folder 185)
      - Creative Arts Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, announcement of 3rd year, undated (Box 4, Folder 186)
        Note in original folder: All copies destroyed and not to be mailed out per MaT 1/24/67. One copy remains in master binders (A-Z and Chronological).
      - Creative Arts Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 2nd year, 1961 March 13 (Box 4, Folder 187)
      - Creative Arts Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1st Year, 1960 June 20 (Box 4, Folder 188)
      - Creative Arts Program Ford Foundation release - Initial announcement, 1960 March 22 (Box 4, Folder 189)
      - Curatorial Training Program cumulative list of awards, undated (Box 4, Folder 190)
      - Curatorial Training Program Ford Foundation release - 7th year awards, 1971 September 21 (Box 4, Folder 191)
      - Curatorial Training Program Ford Foundation release - 6th year awards, 1970 June 10 (Box 4, Folder 192)
      - Curatorial Training Program Ford Foundation release - 5th year awards, 1970 January 2 (Box 4, Folder 193)
      - Curatorial Training Program Ford Foundation release - 4th year awards, 1968 May 27 (Box 4, Folder 194)
      - Curatorial Training Program Ford Foundation release - 3rd year awards, 1967 July 25 (Box 4, Folder 195)
      - Curatorial Training Program Ford Foundation release - 2nd year awards, 1966 July 28 (Box 4, Folder 196)
      - Curatorial Training Program Ford Foundation release - 1st year awards, 1965 May 26 (Box 4, Folder 197)
      - Curatorial Training Program Ford Foundation release - Initial announcement, 1964 January 13 (Box 4, Folder 198)
      - Dallas Civic Opera Company, undated (Box 4, Folder 199)
      - Dallas Theater Center Ford Foundation release - $18,250 grant, 1971 February 23 (Box 4, Folder 200)
      - Dance Notation Bureau Ford Foundation release - $40,000, 1970 May 26 (Box 4, Folder 201)
      - Dance Theatre of Harlem Ford Foundation release - $347,225 grant, 1971 February 23 (Box 4, Folder 202)
      - Dance Theatre of Harlem Ford Foundation release - $315,000, 1970 May 26 (Box 4, Folder 203)
      - Dearborn, City of release - $500,000 grant to Ford Centennial Library, 1967 August 19 (Box 4, Folder 204)
      - Dearborn, City of release - $3 million grant to Ford Centennial Library, 1963 April 12 (Box 4, Folder 205)
      - Detroit Institute of Arts - $2 million: Springwells Park property transfer, 1959 July 29 (Box 4, Folder 206)
      - Detroit Symphony Orchestra release - $2 million grant, 1964 May 21 (Box 4, Folder 207)
      - De Young Memorial Museum release - $4,000 grant, 1968 November 26 (Box 4, Folder 208)
      - Douglas Institute release - $250,000 grant, 1967 May 23 (Box 4, Folder 209)
      - Duke University and University of North Carolina Ford Foundation release - $20,000 grant each, 1969 April 9 (Box 4, Folder 210)
      - Duke University and University of North Carolina Ford Foundation release - $200,000 grants each, 1966 January 7 (Box 4, Folder 211)
      - Duke University and University of North Carolina release - $800,000 grant, 1963 October 27 (Box 4, Folder 212)
      - Directors Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1960 March 9 (Box 4, Folder 213)
      - Directors Program Ford Foundation release - Announcement of 2nd year, 1959 August 20 (Box 4, Folder 214)
      - Directors Program Ford Foundation release - Awards, 1959 February 17 (Box 4, Folder 215)
      - Directors Program Ford Foundation release - Announcement of 1st year, 1958 July 28 (Box 4, Folder 216)
      - East West Players release - $38,500 grant, 1968 July 22 (Box 4, Folder 217)
      - Economic and financial survey Ford Foundation release, 1974 August 6 (Box 4, Folder 218)
        A copy of this press release was found in the preceding file. The copy was reintegrated into the correct file during processing.